<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The orders, rules, and ordinances ordained, devised, and made by the master and keepers or wardens and comminalty of the mystery or art of Stationers of the city of London, for the well governing of that society</title>
            <author>Stationers' Company (London, England)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1678</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 69 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 16 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A53410</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing O403</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R11816</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">13014894</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 13014894</idno>
            <idno type="VID">96532</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A53410)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 96532)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 394:4)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The orders, rules, and ordinances ordained, devised, and made by the master and keepers or wardens and comminalty of the mystery or art of Stationers of the city of London, for the well governing of that society</title>
                  <author>Stationers' Company (London, England)</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[3], 28 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for the Company of Stationers,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1678.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signed: "H. Finch, C. Ri. Rainsford, Fra. North."</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Union Theological Seminary Library, New York.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Stationers' Company (London, England)</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2011-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-02</date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-02</date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:96532:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:96532:1"/>
            <p>ORDERS, RULES AND ORDINANCES, Ordained, Deviſed and Made by the Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of STATIONERS OF The City of <hi>LONDON,</hi> for the well Governing of that Society.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for the Company of <hi>Stationers,</hi> 1678.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="license">
            <pb facs="tcp:96532:2"/>
            <opener>
               <dateline>
                  <date>16 Feb. 1677/8.</date>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            <p>We do allow the Printing of theſe Orders for the Uſe of the Members of the Company.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>
                  <list>
                     <item>Ri. Rainsford.</item>
                     <item>Fra. North.</item>
                  </list>
               </signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="approbation">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:96532:2"/>
            <p>
               <hi rend="blackletterType">TO all to whom theſe Preſents ſhall come,</hi> We the Right Honourable <hi>Heneage</hi> Lord <hi>Finch</hi> Baron of <hi>Daventry,</hi> Lord High Chancellor of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> Sir <hi>Richard Rainsford</hi> Knight, Lord Chief Juſtice of his Majeſties Court of <hi>Kings Bench,</hi> and Sir <hi>Francis North</hi> Knight, Lord Chief Juſtice of the Court of <hi>Common Pleas</hi> at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> ſend Greeting. <hi rend="blackletterType">Whereas,</hi> in a Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute made in the Parliament holden at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> the Twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty Fifth day of <hi>January,</hi> in the Nineteenth Year of the Reign of the late King of Famous Memory, <hi>Henry</hi> the Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venth, for the Weal and Profit of his Subjects, <hi rend="blackletterType">It</hi> was a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt other things Ordained, Eſtabliſhed and Enacted, That no Maſter, Wardens and Fellowſhips of Crafts and Myſteries, or any of them, nor any Rulers of Guilds and Fraternities, ſhould take upon them to make any Acts or Ordinances, nor to Execute any Acts or Ordinances by them then afore-made, in Diſinheritance or Diminution of the Prerogative of the King, nor of any other, nor againſt the Common Profit of the People; But if the ſaid Acts or Ordinances be Examined and Approved by the Chancellor or Treaſurer of <hi>England,</hi> or Chief Juſtices of either Bench, or Three of them, or before both the Juſtices of Aſſize in their Circuit or Progreſs in the Shire where ſuch Acts or Ordinances be made, upon pain of Forfeiture of Forty Pounds for every time that they do contrary, (as by the ſame Statute more plainly doth and may appear.) <hi rend="blackletterType">Know ye,</hi> That the Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> willing and deſiring that the ſaid Act of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment,
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:96532:3"/> be in all things duely obſerved and kept, the Third day of <hi>January,</hi> in the Nine and Twentieth Year of the Reign of our Sovereign Lord <hi>Charles</hi> the Second, by the Grace of God of <hi>England, Scotland, France</hi> and <hi>Ireland</hi> King, <hi>Defender of the Faith,</hi> &amp;c. Have preſented unto us a Book containing divers Orders, Rules and Ordinances by them Ordained, Deviſed and Made, for the well Governing of their Society; And as well for the Conſideration of the good Eſtate thereof, as for the better Governing and Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dering of the ſaid Society, at their humble Suit to us made, to have the ſame Settled and Eſtabliſhed; And that We all and every their ſaid Acts and Ordinances hereafter mention<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, and by them ſo to us exhibited, would Examine, and thoſe and every of them Correct and Amend, and ſo Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prove them in due and convenient manner and form, as the ſaid recited Act of Parliament requireth: <hi rend="blackletterType">Wee</hi> well per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiving and conſidering the ſaid Supplication to be good and reaſonable, according to their deſire, and by the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority of the ſaid Act of Parliament to us given, All and every their Acts and Ordinances ſo to us Exhibited, have Seen, Read and Examined; The Tenor whereof hereafter followeth, <hi>Viz.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:96532:3"/>
            <head>THE Orders, Rules AND ORDINANCES, Ordained, Deviſed and Made By the Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>STATIONERS</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> for the well Governing of that Society.</head>
            <div type="section">
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>IT</hi> is Ordained, That the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Society and their Surceſſors for ever ſhall and may from time to time and at all times hereafter by the appoint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the Maſter, or, in his abſence, of the Wardens of the ſaid Society for the time being Aſſemble themſelves together (as heretofore hath been uſual) and keep Courts at their Common Hall or other convenient place of Meeting within the City of <hi>London</hi> or Liberties thereof, for ſuch Affairs of the ſaid Compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny as have been uſually at ſuch Courts done and diſpatched, wherein Care ſhall be taken as well for the better Ordering, Ruling and Governing of the ſaid Society and the Members thereof, as alſo for the Correction, Redreſs and Reformation of ſuch Abuſes and Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>orders which may happen in the ſaid Society amongſt any the Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers thereof; and ſhall and may there alſo Admit Apprentices to their reſpective Members according to the uſage of the ſaid Society and Laws and Statutes of this Kingdom; And may alſo then make free of the ſaid Society ſuch as have ſerved their Apprenticeſhips or ſuch as ſhall be otherwiſe thought fit to be admitted Freemen there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, as by the ancient Vſage of this Company hath been done and
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:96532:4"/> practiſed: And may alſo at ſuch Courts debate and determine all and every other lawful Act and Acts, thing and things, which ſhall at any time or times appear to the ſaid Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or the greater Number of them there met together fit and conveni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ent, touching or concerning the State or Government of the ſaid Society, or any thing relating thereunto. Which ſaid Courts or Aſſemblies ſhall be called Courts of Aſſiſtants; and to which Courts or Aſſemblies to be held in manner aforeſaid, the ſaid maſter, War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens and Aſſiſtants ſhall come in their Gowns and other decent Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parel, and the ſaid Aſſiſtants ſhall not depart from thence without the leave of the Maſter or one of the Wardens firſt had; and that every perſon being a Member and Aſſiſtant of the ſaid Society, ſhall upon ſummons by the Beadle or other perſon for that purpoſe ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed repair to every ſuch Court or Aſſembly to be holden by the ſaid Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Society, or the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jor part of them, at ſuch hours and times as he or they ſhall be ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed, and ſhall not depart thence without the leave of the Maſter or one of the Wardens firſt had, upon pain that every perſon ſo neg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lecting or diſobeying, not having a ſufficient Excuſe to be allowed by the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them, in a Court of Aſſiſtants, ſhall forfeit and pay for every ſuch Offence to the Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the My<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> the ſumme of One ſhilling.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>IT IS</hi> alſo Ordained, That the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Society ſhall and may yearly and every year from henceforth hold and keep Four Quarter Courts or Aſſemblies (to wit) One in each Quarter, at ſuch times and place within the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, or Liberties thereof, as the ſaid Maſter or War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens of the ſaid Society ſhall appoint: To which ſaid Courts or Aſſemblies the ſaid Maſter or Wardens may cauſe to be ſummoned by their Beadle or other perſon appointed for that purpoſe all the Members of the ſaid Society, or ſo many of them as to the ſaid Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter or Wardens ſhall be thought fit; every of which Members be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing ſo ſummoned, ſhall accordingly appear at every ſuch Court: At all which times all the Orders and Ordinances of the ſaid Society, or ſo many of them as ſhall be held neceſſary, ſhall be then and there diſtinctly read and publiſhed before the Members of the ſaid Society, who ſhall be there Aſſembled, the better to acquaint them with the ſame; and that they may alſo be put in mind of keeping the ſame
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:96532:4"/> according to the Tenor of their Oaths taken at their Admittance into the Freedom of the ſaid Society; and alſo that all perſons who are concern'd to obey the ſame may be left wholly inexcuſable for any diſobedience thereunto. At which ſaid Quarter Courts or Aſſemblies every Member of the ſaid Society ſhall pay to the Ren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Warden of the ſaid Society, [or ſuch other Perſon to be by the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them, at any Court of Aſſiſtants appointed for that purpoſe to demand and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive the ſame] his or their Quarteridge-Money which ſhall be due and payable to the ſaid Society by him or them according to the Rates or Proportions following, <hi>(viz.)</hi> The Maſter, each Warden and every Aſſiſtant of the ſaid Society ſhall pay the ſumme of Two ſhillings Eight pence yearly by Eight pence a Quarter, every per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon which is of the Livery or Cloathing of the ſaid Company ſhall pay the ſumme of Two ſhillings yearly by ſix pence a Quarter, and every perſon of the Yeomanry of the ſaid Society ſhall pay the ſumme of One ſhilling and Four pence yearly, by Four pence every Quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter for ever, towards the ſupport and maintenance of the ſaid So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciety; And every perſon ſo refuſing or delaying to pay the ſame Quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terly upon Demand as aforeſaid, ſhall forfeit and pay to the ſaid Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London</hi> for every ſuch default the ſeveral Rates following, <hi>(Viz.)</hi> Every Aſſiſtant the ſum of Eight pence beſides his Quarteridge, every Livery-man ſix pence beſides his Quarteridge, and every one of the Yeomanry Four pence beſides his Quarteridge.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> for the better avoiding of Diſorders, Noiſe and Confuſion in all Courts of Aſſiſtants or Aſſemblies as aforeſaid, It is Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dained, that every Member of the ſaid Court ſhall always keep ſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lence at the Command or deſire of the Maſter or Wardens; and when any Matter or thing ſhall be moved or debated in any Court of Aſſiſtants or Aſſembly as aforeſaid, there ſhall but one perſon ſpeak at one time to the matter in debate: And all Debates, Propoſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions and Diſcourſes ſhall be addreſſed to the Maſter, or in his ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence to him who ſhall poſſeſs the Chair only (which perſon to ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ply the place of Maſter, in his abſence ſhall be choſen by the major part of the Members being of the Court of Aſſiſtants there preſent) that ſo the Opinion and Iudgement of every Member may be heard and known, and alſo that every perſon ſhall ſpeak bare-headed, and that every perſon except the Maſter, (or that perſon who in his ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence ſhall poſſeſs the Chair,) who ſhall at any time ſpeak as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:96532:5"/> ſhall addreſs his diſcourſe to the Maſter or him who ſhall in his abſence as aforeſaid poſſeſs the Chair: And that all <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ebates be ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rious and without any Speeches or Expreſſions that may <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ſtly give Offence in the ſaid Court or any perſon therein, upon pain to forſeit and pay for every Offence againſt this O<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>der to the Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of Stationers of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, the ſumme of One ſhilling.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>IT IS</hi> likewiſe Ordained, That the full and abſolute power of Nomination and Election of Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, Members of the Livery, and of all other Officers of the ſaid So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciety, ſhall always be and remain as uſually heretofore hath been, only in the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Society or the major part of them in a Court or Courts of Aſſiſtants aſſem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled; In which Nomination and Choices they ſhall obſerve the Ancient ways, Time and Method of Nomination and Election which have heretofore been obſerved and uſed in the ſaid Society.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND IT IS</hi> further Ordained, That the ſaid Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them in a Court or Courts of Aſſiſtants aſſembled yearly and every year according to their ancient Vſage, and at their uſual time ſhall Elect and chooſe one diſcreet, honeſt and able perſon, being a Member of the ſaid Court of Aſſiſtants, to be Maſter of the ſaid Society for one year then next following; which Perſon ſo Elected ſhall forthwith accept the Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice of Maſter of the ſaid Society, and take the Oath hereafter in theſe Preſents for that purpoſe appointed, and ſhall hear the ſame Charges, and perform the ſame Duties as other Maſters before him have heretofore uſually done; and ſhall continue therein for one whole Year, and untill a New Maſter of and for the ſaid Company ſhall be Elected and ſworn. And if it ſhall happen that the ſaid Maſter ſo to be Elected, ſhall dye, or be removed before the end of his year, the Wardens and Aſſiſtants or the major part of them may forthwith at a Court of Aſſiſtants to be by the ſaid Wardens appointed, proceed to a New Election in manner and form aforeſaid, according to the Cuſtom of the ſaid Society, of ſome fit perſon being one of the ſaid Court of Aſſiſtants, to ſerve in the Office or place of Maſter of the ſaid Society for the remainder of that time which the deceaſed or re<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ed Maſter ought to have ſerved. And if any per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon choſen in ſuch manner as is by this Ordinance appointed, to be
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:96532:5"/> Maſter of the ſaid Society, ſhall refuſe to accept the ſaid Office and take the ſaid Oath (having no reaſonable or juſt Impediment that may hinder him ſo to doe, and which ſhall be allowed to be ſo by the Court of Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Society or the major part of them then preſent) then ſuch perſon ſo refuſing to take upon him the Exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cution of the ſaid Office, and to take the Oath aforeſaid, ſhall for ſuch his refuſal pay forthwith to the ſaid Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> the ſumme of Twenty pounds, unleſs upon his application to the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſiſtants then preſent, they ſhall think fit to excuſe him upon payment of a more moderate Fine, to be by them impoſed, not under Ten pounds, to be paid to the ſaid Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London.</hi> And the Maſter, War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them in a Court or Courts of Aſſiſtants aſſembled, ſhall forthwith upon ſuch refuſal Elect in manner and form aforeſaid one other fit perſon to be Maſter of the ſaid Society inſtead of the perſon ſo refuſing, and for ſuch time as the perſon ſo refuſing ſhould have been Maſter if he had not refuſed; and untill there ſhall be a New Maſter choſen who ſhall take upon him the Execution of the ſaid Office and take the ſaid Oath, the ſame Method for Election ſhall be obſerved and Penalties incurred for refuſal.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>ALSO</hi> it is Ordained, That the Maſter, Wardens and Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſtants, or the major part of them, ſhall according to their ancient uſage at ſuch Court of Aſſiſtants, to be held at the ſaid uſual time, Elect and chooſe one of the Members of the ſaid Socie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty (being qualified as aforeſaid) to be firſt or Vpper Warden of the ſaid Society for one whole year from thence next enſuing; Which perſon ſo Elected ſhall forthwith accept of the ſaid Office, and take the Oath hereafter in theſe preſents for that purpoſe appointed, and ſhall continue therein for One whole year, and untill ſome new firſt or Vpper Warden ſhall be elected and choſen in his place, and ſhall bear an equal part with his Vnder-Warden in the making of an Election-Dinner for the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants and Livery, according to the ancient cuſtom of this Company, (this Company making to him and the Vnder-warden the ſame allowance which hath been uſually made to other Wardens upon the ſame oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caſion.) And in caſe of the death or removal of ſuch firſt or Vpper-warden,
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:96532:6"/> warden, the Maſter remaining, Warden and Aſſiſtants, or the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jor part of them in a Court of Aſſiſtants, may forthwith proceed to a New Election in manner and form aforeſaid, according to the Cuſtom of the ſaid Society, of ſome fit perſon, being one of the ſaid Court of Aſſiſtants, to ſerve in the Office or Place of Firſt or Vp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per-warden of the ſaid Society for the remainder of that time which the deceaſed or removed Firſt or Vpper-Warden of the ſaid Society ought to have ſerved. And if any perſon choſen as aforeſaid to be Firſt or Vpper-warden of the ſaid Society, ſhall refuſe to accept the ſaid Office, and take the Oath in manner aforeſaid (having no juſt or reaſonable Impediment or Excuſe that may hinder him ſo to doe, and which ſhall be allowed by the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Society, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſiſtants) then ſuch perſon ſo Elected and refuſing to take upon him the Execution of the ſaid Office, and to take the Oath afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, ſhall for ſuch his refuſal forthwith pay to the ſaid Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or art of <hi>Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioners</hi> of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, the ſumme of Twenty four pounds, except he Served or Fined for Firſt or Vpper-warden the preceding-year, and then for his refuſal in ſuch Caſe he ſhall forfeit and pay but ſix pounds. But if any perſon ſhall be choſen firſt or Vpper-warden as aforeſaid, who never ſerved firſt or Vpper-warden of the ſaid Society before, ſhall make his applications to the Cours of Aſſiſtants, the ſaid Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſiſtants, if they think fit, may excuſe him from ſerving in the ſaid Office upon payment of a more moderate Fine, to be by them in a Court of Aſſiſtants impoſed, not under Twelve pounds; and that then the Maſter remaining, War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them, in a Court of Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants, ſhall forthwith upon ſuch refuſal Elect in manner and form aforeſaid, one other fit perſon to be firſt or Vpper-warden of the ſaid Society inſtead of the perſon ſo refuſing, and for ſuch time as he ſhould have ſerved firſt or Vpper-warden by ſuch Election, if he had not refuſed, and untill there ſhall be a firſt or Vpper-Warden cho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſen, who ſhall take upon him the Execution of the ſaid Office, and take the ſaid Oath, the ſame Method ſhall be obſerved, and Penalties incurred upon every ſuch refuſal.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> it is likewiſe Ordained, That the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them, according to their an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tient uſage at ſuch Courts of Aſſiſtants to be holden at ſuch uſual
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:96532:6"/> time ſhall Elect and chooſe one other Member of the ſaid Society (being qualified as aforeſaid) to be ſecond or Vnder-warden of the ſaid Society for One whole year from thence next enſuing; which perſon ſo Elected ſhall forthwith accept the ſaid Office, and take the Oath hereafter in theſe Preſents for that purpoſe appointed, and ſhall continue therein for One whole year, and untill ſome one ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond or Vnder-warden ſhall be Elected and ſworn in his place, and ſhall bear an Equal part with his Vpper-warden in the making of an Election-Dinner for the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants and Livery, according to the ancient cuſtom of this Company; this Company making to him and his Vpper-warden the ſame allow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance which hath been uſually made to other Wardens upon the ſame occaſion. (And in caſe of the death or removal of ſuch ſecond or Vnder-warden, the Maſter remaining, Warden a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>d Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them, may forthwith pro<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>eed to a New Election in manner and form aforeſaid, according to the cuſtom of the ſaid Society, of ſome fit perſon, being of the ſaid Court of Aſſiſtants, to ſerve in the place or Office of ſecond or Vnder-warden of the ſaid Society, for the remainder of the time which the deceaſed or re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moved ſecond or Vnder-warden ought to have ſerved.) And if any perſon choſen as aforeſaid, to be ſecond or Vnder-warden of the ſaid Society ſhall refuſe to accept the ſaid Office, and to take the Oath in manner aforeſaid (having no reaſonable or juſt Impediment or Excuſe that may hinder him ſo to doe, and which ſhall be ſo allow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Society, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſiſtants) Then ſuch perſon ſo Elected, and refuſing to take upon him the Execution of the ſaid Office, and take the Oath aforeſaid, ſhall for ſuch his Refuſal forth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>with pay to the Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> the ſumm of Twenty pounds; But if ſuch perſon that ſhall be ſo Elected, hath ſerved Second or Vnder-warden the preceding year, then the ſaid Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſiſtants, if they think fit, may excuſe him from the ſaid Office, upon payment of ſome other ſmaller ſumme of money, ſo as it be not under Five pounds; and although any perſon which ſhall be choſen ſecond or Vnder-warden as aforeſaid, hath not ſerved ſecond or under-Warden of the ſaid Society before, yet if he ſhall make his application to the Court of Aſſiſtants, the ſaid Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them in a Court of aſſiſtants, if they ſhall think fit, may excuſe him from ſerving in the
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:96532:7"/> ſaid Office, upon payment of a ſmaller ſumme of Money than the ſaid Twenty pounds, ſo as it be not under Ten pounds, and that then the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſiſtants, ſhall forthwith upon ſuch refuſal Elect in manner and form aforeſaid one other fit perſon to be Second or under-Warden of the ſaid Society, inſtead of the perſon ſo refuſing, and for ſuch time as he ſhould have ſerved Second or under-Warden by ſuch Election if he had not refuſed, and untill there ſhall be a ſecond or under-Warden choſen, who ſhall take upon him the Exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cution of the ſaid Office, and take the ſaid Oath, the ſame method ſhall be obſerved, and penalties incurred upon every ſuch refu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſal.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND IT IS</hi> further Ordained, That the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Society, or the major part of them ſhall and may from time to time, and at any time or times hereafter, when they ſhall think fit, at a Court of Aſſiſtants, make choice of ſuch and ſo many of the Members of the ſaid Society (who have paid their Fines for not ſerving, or elſe have ſerved according to the Cuſtom of the ſaid Society in the Office or Place of Renter-warden of the ſaid Society) as they or the major part of them ſhall think fit to be Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants to the ſaid Maſter and Wardens, and of common Council of the ſaid Society; and that every perſon and perſons ſo choſen as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, ſhall before he or they take upon him or them his Office or place of an Aſſiſtant as aforeſaid, or ſit in any Court of Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Society, take an Oath before the ſaid Maſter, Wardens and Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants of the ſaid Society, or the major part of them; which Oath is to be adminiſtred in a Court of the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants of the ſaid Society, or the major part of them, according to the form for that purpoſe hereafter appointed. Every which ſaid perſon or perſons ſo choſen to be an Aſſiſtant as aforeſaid, ſhall after his being ſworn as aforeſaid, pay to the Clerk of the ſaid So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciety for Adminiſtring the Oath, and Regiſtring his Name, the uſual Fee of Ten Shillings, and to the Beadle of the ſaid Society his uſual Fee of Five Shillings.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> it is hereby likewiſe Ordained, That within ſome time convenient after the Election and Oath taken by the new Maſter and Wardens of the ſaid Society as aforeſaid, not exceed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing two moneths, the laſt Maſter and Wardens, and every of them, ſhall give a true and juſt accompt in writing (unto ſuch perſons
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:96532:7"/> as ſhall be appointed by the then Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Society, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants, Auditors for that purpoſe) of all Iewels, Plate, Money, Linnen, Charters, Deeds, Evidences, Obligations, Writings, Books and Papers whatſoever, and of all other Goods and Chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels whatſoever belonging to the ſaid Society, and which did at any time come to his or their hands, charge or cuſtody; and ſhall like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe ſafely deliver them to the Maſter and Wardens then in being, together with his or their Key or Keys; and alſo all other things whatſoever belonging to the ſaid Society, which are or were in his or their cuſtody, and not accompted for, upon pain of Forfeiting to the uſe of the ſaid Society for every Month that every ſuch perſon or perſons ſhall neglect to Accompt as aforeſaid, or detain any of the ſaid Premiſſes after the time limited hereby over and above the full value of the ſame (ſuch perſon or perſons having no juſt Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pediment for ſo doing, which ſhall be ſo allowed by the Maſter, War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſtants) the ſumme of One hundred pounds. And it is likewiſe Ordained, that the ſaid Accompts with the Inventory, and ſuch other things as ſhall be ſo delivered up, ſhall immediately after the Auditing and Allowance thereof be fairly entred by the Clerk of the ſaid Society into a Book for that purpoſe provided, which Book ſhall be ſafely kept by him in his Office.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> alſo it is further Ordained, That the common Seal of the ſaid Society, together with the Plate, Iewels, Goods, Charters, Writings, Evidences, and all other things belonging to the ſaid Society, ſhall remain and be in one or more Cheſt or Cheſts, which ſaid Cheſt or Cheſts ſhall alſo ſtand in the Hall or ſuch other place as the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jor part of them in a Court of Aſſiſtants ſhall direct, and to which there ſhall be three ſeveral Locks and Keys, the cuſtody of one of which ſaid Keys ſhall be in the Maſter of the ſaid Society for the time being, the cuſtody of another ſhall be in the firſt or upper War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den for the time being, and the cuſtody of the third ſhall be in the ſecond or under Warden for the time being, during their reſpective Offices, and untill their Accompts ſhall be audited only. And if it ſhall happen the ſaid Maſter or either of the ſaid Wardens to be ſick or travail out of the ſaid City, or ſhall abſent himſelf for Four<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teen days, that then in ſuch caſe every ſuch Maſter and Warden
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:96532:8"/> reſpectively ſhall leave his or their Key or Keys with ſome other ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſt and able perſon or perſons, being one of the ſaid Aſſiſtants, ſo that the ſaid Companies affairs may not ſuffer prejudice by want thereof. Vpon pain to forfeit for every ſuch default to the ſaid Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, the ſumme of Five pounds.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>ALSO</hi> it is further Ordained, That no Leaſes, Demiſes, An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nuities, Grants, Gifts or Bargains and Sales of what na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture or kind ſoever, of any Houſe or Houſes, Lands, Tenements, or other thing or things whatſoever appertaining to the ſaid Socie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, nor any Obligations, Bills or Specialties whatſoever, ſhall at any time be granted by or paſs under the Common Seal of the ſaid Society, unleſs the ſame be ordered ſo to be by the Maſter, War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants, upon pain that the Maſter and each Warden which ſhall be maſter or Warden at the time of ſuch offence, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ffending contrary to this Ordinance, ſhall forthwith be Disfranchiſed, and pay each of them for ſuch their Offence, to the Maſter and Keepers or wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, over and above the damage which the ſaid Socie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty ſhall receive for ſuch their offence, the ſumme of one hundred pounds a piece.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> alſo it is Ordained, That the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants of the ſaid Society, or the major part of them, in a Court of Aſſiſtants, when and as often as they ſhall think fit, may Elect, chooſe and admit into the Livery or Cloathing of the ſaid Society, ſuch perſon and perſons free of the ſaid Society, as they ſhall think fit; and that after Election of any perſon into the Livery or Cloath<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing aforeſaid, the Maſter of the ſaid Society ſhall cauſe the Beadle of the ſaid Society to put upon him ſo elected a Livery Gown, after the manner heretofore accuſtomed in the ſaid Society; and then the ſaid Maſter ſhall put upon his ſhoulder a party-coloured Hood made after the uſual manner; after which the ſaid Maſter and Wardens, each in their order, ſhall give to ſuch perſon and perſons his and their hands, ſaying theſe words, <hi>(Videl<hi rend="sup">t.</hi>) BROTHER, you are Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted to the Cloathing of this Company;</hi> or words to that effect; and that every perſon which ſhall be elected and choſen of the Livery or Cloathing of the ſaid Society, ſhall upon ſuch his admiſſion into
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:96532:8"/> the Livery or Cloathing as aforeſaid, according to the ancient uſage of the ſaid Society, pay to the ſaid Maſter and Keepers or Wardens: and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> the ſumme of Twenty pounds for a Fee or Income for ſuch his or their admiſſion as aforeſaid, and to the Clerk of this Society his uſual Fee of Ten ſhillings, and to the Beadle of this Society his uſual Fee of Five ſhillings; and if any ſuch perſon ſo elected into the Cloathing as aforeſaid, ſhall refuſe to accept thereof, having no reaſonable cauſe, and to be ſo allowed by the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them, in a Court of Aſſiſtants; then he ſhall pay to the Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> for ſuch refuſal, the ſumme of Forty pou<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ds.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> it is further Ordained, that all thoſe who ſhall be of the Livery or Cloathing of the ſaid Society, ſhall from time to time upon the Beadles ſummons for that purpoſe, meet at ſuch place and time as ſhall be appointed by the Maſter and Wardens of the ſaid Society; and alſo that every perſon being duely ſummoned as aforeſaid, and ſhall make default, not having a reaſonable Excuſe, or ſhall depart without the leave of the Maſter or Wardens, or one of them, ſhall for every ſuch Default pay to the ſaid Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> the ſumme of one Shilling.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> alſo it is Ordained, That every year yearly in a Court of Aſſiſtants, to be holden as aforeſaid, at the uſual time, the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them then pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent, may Elect and chooſe one honeſt, diſcreet and able man, being of the Livery of the ſaid Society, who ſhall bear the Title of Renter-warden of the ſaid Society for One year next enſuing, and till ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther ſhall be choſen and ſworn in his place; and in caſe of the death or Removal of any Renter-warden, the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſiſtants, ſhall forthwith proceed to a New Election of a Renter-warden in manner and form aforeſaid; which perſon ſo Elected, ſhall forthwith accept the ſaid Office, and take the Oath hereafter for that purpoſe in theſe Preſents mentioned, and alſo ſhall diligently attend the Maſter and Wardens upon their ſummons, and carefully collect and receive all Quarteridges due from and payable by all and every or any of the members of this Society, and alſo all the Rents due to the Maſter
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:96532:9"/> and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> upon all or any Leaſe or Leaſes whatſoever, already made or hereafter to be made by the ſaid Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London;</hi> and ſhall alſo at the uſual time, to wit, within One month after ſome other perſon ſhall be ſworn in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the ſaid Office or ſuch other longer time as ſhall be appointed by the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſiſtants render to the ſaid Maſter, Wardens and Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſtants, or ſuch other perſon as the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants ſhall appoint, a true, plain, perfect and juſt Accompt in writing, of all ſuch Moneys which he hath received, and Disburſments which he hath made (during his time of being Renter-warden) for the uſe of the ſaid Society, and ſhall ſpeedily make payment of what ſhall remain in his hands due upon ſuch Accompt, and deliver his Books and all other Papers or things whatſoever, which may concern the ſaid Society, to the Maſter and Wardens, or ſuch other perſon or perſons as the Maſter and Wardens ſhall appoint, upon pain that every perſon offending againſt this Ordinance, ſhall pay to the Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> for every months time that he ſhall after requeſt or ſummons in that behalf made, refuſe or delay to make ſuch Accompt, the ſumme of Five pounds; and for every months time (after ſuch Accompt ſtated) that the Moneys which ſhall be due upon the foot of ſuch accompt to the ſaid Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the myſtery or art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or any part thereof ſhall remain unpaid, the ſum of Five pounds (he having no reaſonable Impediment or Excuſe which ſhall be ſo allowed by the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſiſtants, for his failor therein.)</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> further it is likewiſe Ordained, That after the Election of the Renter-warden by the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſiſtants, as aforeſaid, if the perſon ſo Elected, ſhall refuſe to accept the ſaid Office, and take the ſaid Oath in manner aforeſaid, having no reaſonable or juſt Impediment or Excuſe that may hinder him ſo to doe, and which ſhall be allowed by the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Society, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſiſtants, then ſuch perſon ſo Elected, and refuſing to take upon him the Execution
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:96532:9"/> of the ſaid office, ſhall for ſuch his refuſal forthwith pay to the Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or art <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> the ſumme of Fifty pounds. But if any perſon which ſhall be choſen Renter-warden as aforeſaid, ſhall make his application to the Court of Aſſiſtants, the ſaid Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſiſtants, if they think fit, may excuſe him upon payment of a ſmaller ſumme of money, ſo as it be not under the ſumme of Twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty four pounds. And alſo it is likewiſe ordained, That every per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon who ſhall hereafter ſerve in the ſaid place or office of Renter-warden to the ſaid Society, according to the ancient uſage of the ſaid Society, ſhall every year upon the day that the Lord Maior of <hi>London</hi> ſhall be preſented and ſworn at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> (in the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Hall of the ſaid Society) or at ſuch other place as the Maſter and Wardens ſhall appoint, at his coſts and charges find and pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vide one competent and ſufficient Dinner for the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, and all the Members of the Livery of the ſaid Society. And if default ſhall be made hereof, that then every ſuch perſon ſhall forfeit and pay for ſuch his default to the Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> the ſumme of Fifty pounds.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> it is likewiſe Ordained, That after the Election of any perſon to be Renter-warden as aforeſaid, and his accepting of the ſaid Office, and taking of the ſaid Oath, then the Maſter and Wardens of the ſaid Society, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſiſtants, ſhall forthwith proceed to the Election of an Aſſiſtant Renter-warden, who is to be aſſiſtant upon all neceſſary occaſions to the preſent Renter-warden, which ſaid aſſiſtant Renter-warden the next year following (or ſooner, if the preſent Renter-warden ſhould happen to dye or be removed) at the uſual time, according to the ancient Vſage of the ſaid Society, ſhall be elected for the ſucceed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing year, if the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſiſtants, ſhall think fit.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> alſo it is likewiſe Ordained, That the Maſter, War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens and Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Society, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſiſtants, ſhall and may when and as often as need ſhall require, Elect and chooſe one fit perſon to be Clerk of the ſaid Society, for the entring and regiſtring of all Decrees, Ordinances, Acts, Agreements, Orders and things whatſoever, made or to be made in their Courts or Aſſemblies afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid,
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:96532:10"/> and to do all other things pertinent to the ſaid Office; which ſaid perſon ſo Elected ſhall forthwith take the Oath for that purpoſe herein after appointed: And alſo the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants of the ſaid Society, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſiſtants, may upon juſt and reaſonable cauſe remove and diſplace ſuch Clerk from his ſaid Office, and in form aforeſaid Elect another fit perſon for the Execution thereof.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> alſo it is further Ordained, That the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants, ſhall and may when and as often as need ſhall require, Elect and chooſe one fit perſon to be Beadle to the ſaid Society, who ſhall take the Oath hereafter in theſe preſents for that purpoſe appointed, and ſhall at all times be attendant upon the ſaid Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants in Court, and Maſter and Wardens out of Court, when he ſhall be thereunto required or commanded by them; and ſhall alſo when he ſhall be thereunto required by the Maſter or War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens of the ſaid Society (and not otherwiſe) diligently ſummon and warn every one of the Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Society, and others if he ſhall be ſo directed, to attend the ſaid Maſter and Wardens as Courts or other Meetings which ſhall be appointed by the ſaid Maſter or Wardens; and alſo the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or the maior part of them in Court, ſhall and may upon juſt and reaſonable cauſe to them appearing, remove and diſplace ſuch Beadle from his ſaid Office, and in form aforeſaid Elect one other fit perſon for the Execution thereof.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> it is hereby further Ordained, That the ſaid Maſter and Wardens, or the major part of them in Court ſhall and may yearly according to the cuſtom of the ſaid Society, Elect and chooſe ſuch and ſo many perſons of the ſaid Society as they ſhall think fit to attend the ſaid Maſter, Wardens, Aſſiſtants and Livery, as Whiflers or Vſhers in any Services to which they ſhall be appoint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, at ſuch times and in ſuch manner as ſhall be appointed by the ſaid Maſter or Wardens, upon pain that every perſon neglecting or refuſing to attend as aforeſaid, ſhall pay to the Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> the ſumme of Ten ſhillings.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> alſo it is hereby further Ordained, That every perſon what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever that now is or hereafter ſhall be a member of the ſaid Society, ſhall at all times from henceforth contribute his proportion
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:96532:10"/> in common with others of the ſaid Society, as is uſual in other Companyes in <hi>London,</hi> of all charges, ſumme and ſummes of Money and Taxes whatſoever, which ſhall be at any time charged upon the ſaid Company, or ſhall be Expended or neceſſary to be Expended for the welfare and good Eſtate of the ſaid Company; which proportio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nable part ſhall be aſſeſſed and impoſed upon him by the ſaid Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Society, or the major part of them in Court, who are hereby Impowered to make ſuch Aſſeſſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments; and that every perſon who ſhall refuſe or delay to pay his proportionable ſhare of money to be aſſeſſed as aforeſaid, ſhall pay to the ſaid Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> ſuch reaſonable Fine not exceeding Five pounds, over and above ſo much money which ſhall be aſſeſſed as aforeſaid for any of the uſes aforeſaid, as the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Society, or the major part of them in Court ſhall think fit.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> alſo it is likewiſe Ordained, That none of the members of the ſaid Society ſhall at any time hereafter, revile, abuſe or defame in words or otherwiſe, the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Society, or any of them, or any other member of the ſame Society, but ſhall at all times well demean themſelves, and be of good behaviour and civil converſation both in word and deeds. <hi>And</hi> it is further Ordained, That if any perſon of the court of Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants or common Council of this Society, ſhall infringe this Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinance, or any part thereof, he ſhall be lyable to be Expelled and put out of his place as an Aſſiſtant, or one of the common Council of the ſaid Society; and after ſuch expulſion ſhall not be capable of being choſen again, untill he or they ſhall pay to the Maſter and Wardens of the ſaid Society, ſuch Fine not exceeding Five pounds as the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſiſtants, ſhall Impoſe upon him or them for ſuch his or their Offence; and alſo upon pain that every other Member of the ſaid Society offending againſt this Ordinance, ſhall forfeit and pay to the Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> ſuch Fine not exceeding Twenty Shillings as the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants of the ſaid Society, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſiſtants, ſhall Impoſe upon him or them for ſuch his or their Offence.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <pb n="18" facs="tcp:96532:11"/>
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> alſo it is further Ordained, That if any perſon being a Member of this Society, being of the Court of Aſſiſtants, or a Livery man of the ſaid Society, when commanded by the Maſter and Wardens to attend in his Gown and Hood, ſhall at any time ren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der himſelf diſobedient to the ſaid Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or any of them, or ſhall hold any private meeting, or give counſel to or confederate with any perſon or perſons, to reſiſt or oppoſe the ſaid Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or any of them, in their law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Government, or ſhall do any act or thing which may in any wiſe prejudice the ſaid Society, or may tend to the breach of any of the aforeſaid lawfull conſtitutions and Ordinances, Then every perſon ſo offending, for ſuch his Offence againſt any part of this Ordinance ſhall forfeit and pay to the Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> ſuch Fine not exceeding Five pounds, as the Maſter, War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants, ſhall impoſe upon him or them for ſuch his or their Offence.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>ALSO</hi> it is Ordained, That if the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants of the ſaid Society, or any of them, or any other Member of the ſaid Society, ſhall at any time hereafter, reveal, diſcloſe or make known any of the lawful ſecrets, conferences or conſultations of the ſaid Society, tending to the diſcredit, damage or prejudice of the ſaid Society, or any of the Governours, Officers or Members thereof, That then ſuch perſon ſo offending, be he Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter, Warden or one of the Aſſiſtants, ſhall be excluded from the Court of Aſſiſtants or common Council of the ſaid Society, untill he hath paid ſuch Fine, not exceeding the ſumme of Five pounds, as the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, or the major part of them in Court, ſhall impoſe upon him or them for ſuch his or their Offence. And every other member ſo offending, ſhall forfeit and pay to the Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty, of the myſtery or art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> ſuch Fine not exceeding Forty ſhillings, as the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants or the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jor part of them in a Court of Aſſiſtants, ſhall impoſe upon him or them.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> he it further Ordained, That when any difference or dif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferences ſhall hereafter ariſe between any member and mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers of this Company for any Copy, Right, or any thing relating to
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:96532:11"/> Printing, Book-ſelling or Book-binding, That then before any Acti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on or ſuit be commenced, they ſhall firſt make their application to the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants in a Court of Aſſiſtants, and give them true information of the ground and occaſion of ſuch Difference or controverſie; which ſaid Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, in a Court of Aſſiſtants, are hereby authorized to hear all parties con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerned, and to uſe their utmoſt Endeavours to compoſe ſuch Difference and Differences, without the trouble and charge of going to Law, upon pain that every member that ſhall for any of the Cauſes afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid commence any Suit or Suits, without application made as aforeſaid, ſhall forfeit and pay to the Maſter and Keepers or War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> the ſumme of Ten pounds.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> whereas ſince the making of the late Act of Parliament made in his now Majeſties Reign, intituled, <hi>An Act for pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venting the frequent abuſes in Printing Seditious, Treaſonable and unlicenſed Books and Pamphlets, and for regulating of Printing and Printing-preſſes,</hi> ſeveral members of the ſaid Society have Erected Preſſes contrary to the ſaid Act, and therewithall have printed ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral ſeditious, treaſonable, ſchiſmatical, ſcandalous and unlicen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed Books and Pamphlets, to the great Scandal of the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany, and the Government thereof: For the future prevention whereof, It is hereby Ordained, That no Member of this Compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny ſhall hereafter Erect or cauſe to be Erected, any Preſs or Preſſes for Printing, or any Printing-houſe or Printing-houſes; nor ſhall knowingly Demiſe or Lett, or ſuffer to be held or uſed any Houſe, Vault or Cellar, or other Room whatſoever, for a Printing-houſe or place to print in, unleſs he or they who Erect ſuch Preſs or Preſſes, Printing-houſe or Printing-houſes, or ſhall ſo knowingly demiſe or lett ſuch Houſes, Cellar, Vault or Room, or ſuffer the ſame to be uſed, ſhall firſt give Notice to the Maſter and Wardens of the ſaid Society, or one of them, of the Erecting ſuch Demiſe, or Preſſes, Printing-houſe or Printing-houſes, or of ſuch Demiſe, or ſuffering to work or Print, upon pain of forfeiting the ſumme of Ten pounds for every Offence to be committed contrary to any of the Clauſes of this Ordinance, and Forty ſhillings a day during every day that the ſame ſhall continue, to be paid to the Maſter and Keep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers or Wardens and Commonalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> to the uſe of the Poor of the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <pb n="20" facs="tcp:96532:12"/>
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> alſo it is further Ordained, That no Member or Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers of the ſaid Society, ſhall at any time from henceforth erect, or cauſe or procure or ſuffer to be erected any private Preſs or Preſſes, commonly called <hi>A Preſs in a hole,</hi> nor ſhall countenance, aſſiſt or contribute towards the erecting or ſetting up of any ſuch private Preſſe or Preſſes, or ſhall knowingly accommodate, furniſh, or ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ply any ſuch private Preſſe or Preſſes, with Paper or any other materials for Printing, or contribute towards the ſame, or pay or contribute towards the payment of any Wages, Sallary or Hire, to any perſon or perſons, for the working at any private Preſſe or Preſſes, or towards the payment of any Rent or Reward for any Houſe or place where ſuch private Preſſe or Preſſes ſhall be Erected and ſet up, or connive at or conceal any ſuch Preſſe or Preſſes, Houſe or Houſes, place or places, or the Name or Names of any ſuch perſon or perſons that ſhall erect or cauſe to be erected, or con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tribute towards the erecting, furniſhing, ſupplying, working at, or preparing work for any ſuch private Preſſe or Preſſes, or ſhall wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lingly and knowingly buy, barter, or contract for any Impreſſion or part of any Impreſſion, of any Book or Books, or part of Book, Pamphlet or Paper; or knowingly bind, ſtitch, put together for ſale, publiſh, diſpoſe, or diſperſe any Book, Pamphlet or Paper, which ſhall be Imprinted at any ſuch private Preſſe or Preſſes, upon pain that every Member in any of the ſaid caſes offending, ſhall be lyable to be disfranchiſed for ſuch Offence, or to pay to the Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> ſuch reaſonable Fine, not ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding Fifty pounds, as the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Company, or the major part of them in a Court of Aſſiſtants, ſhall Impoſe upon him for ſuch his Offence. And for the better diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>covery of all ſuch private Printing-preſſes, commonly called <hi>Preſſes in Holes,</hi> it is further Ordained, That every perſon and perſons that ſhall diſcover any ſuch private Printing-preſſe to the Maſter and Wardens of the ſaid Society, or either of them, ſhall have the ſumm of Five pounds, or what more the Maſter or Wardens ſhall think fit, as a Reward for ſuch his Service, to be paid to him out of the common Stock of the ſaid Society, by the ſaid Maſter or Wardens, or one of them, and ſhall be allowed in their or any of their Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compts.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <pb n="21" facs="tcp:96532:12"/>
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> it is likewiſe further Ordained, That no member or members of the ſaid Society, ſhall imploy either to work at the Caſe or Preſſe, or otherwiſe about his Printing, any Iourneyman-Printer, Freeman or Forreigner, or other perſon whatſoever, that ſhall have offended in any of the caſes mentioned in the Two laſt before-mentioned Ordinances, for the ſpace of Three months next after due proof thereof made, either by Confeſſion or otherwiſe, to the Court of Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Society, and notice thereof given to the wheral Maſter-Printers of the ſaid Society, without Licenſe from the Maſter or Wardens of the ſaid Society firſt had and obtain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed; Vpon pain that every Member ſo offending after Notice given as aforeſaid, ſhall forfeit and pay to the Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> the ſumme of Ten ſhillings for every month that he or they ſhall Imploy ſuch Offender or Offenders as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> it is likewiſe further Ordained, That no member or mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers of the ſaid Society, ſhall knowingly permit or ſuffer his Apprentice or Apprentices, or Covenant-ſervants, at any time to work at any Preſſe or Preſſes, any matter or thing whatſoever pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hibited by the ſaid Act of Parliament, and the before-mentioned Two Ordinances: and that if any ſuch Maſter-Printer ſhall at any time diſcover or know that any of his Apprentices or Covenant-ſervants ſhall offend in any of the ſaid Caſes, That then ſuch Maſter-Prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter ſhall cauſe ſuch Apprentice or Apprentices, or Covenant-ſervants, forthwith to be brought to the Chamberlain of the City of <hi>London</hi> for the time being, and make complaint of all ſuch his and their Offences, to the end that ſuch Offender and Offenders may be puniſhed according to the ancient cuſtom of the ſaid City, Vpon pain that every Maſter-Printer not effectually putting in Execution this Ordinance, or faintly proſecuting the ſame, ſhall forfeit and pay to the Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the My<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> the ſumme of Forty ſhillings.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> it is alſo Ordained, That no Maſter-Printer, or other Printer or Workman, being a member of this Society, ſhall teach, direct or inſtruct any perſon or perſons whatſoever, other than his or their own Legitimate Son or Sons, in this Art or Myſtery of
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:96532:13"/> Printing, who is not actually bound as an Apprentice to ſome law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful authoriſed Printer; Vpon pain that every perſon ſo offending, ſhall forfeit and pay to the Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Commonalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> the ſumme of Five pounds.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> alſo it is hereby further Ordained, That no member or members of the ſaid Society, ſhall hereafter Erect or ſet up, or cauſe to be erected or ſet up, or countenance, or contribute to the Erecting or ſetting up of any Printing-preſſe or Preſſes, for any new Printing-houſe or Houſes, or ſhall ſupply or furniſh the ſame with any Materials for Printing, untill the now Legal Maſter-Printers and their Printing-houſes be reduced according to the di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rection of the aforeſaid late Act of Parliament, Vpon pain of for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feiting the ſumme of Fifty pounds for every ſuch Offence, and Twenty pounds a month for every month that the ſame ſhall conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nue, to be paid to the Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> it is alſo hereby further Ordained, That if any Iour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neyman Printer, or other perſon, being a member of the ſaid Society, ſhall work at any private illegal Preſs, and not diſcover the ſame within Two days after ſuch working as aforeſaid, to the Maſter and Wardens of the ſaid Society, or any of them, or ſhall knowingly work at or upon the Printing of any ſeditious or ſcan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dalous Book, Pamphlet or Paper, or any other Book or Books, or part of any Book or Books imprinted wrongfully and without leave or Aſſignment of the lawful Owner, the ſole printing whereof law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully belonging to the ſaid Society, or to any other perſon or perſons, or ſhall knowingly bind, ſtitch, or ſow together any ſuch Book or Books, That then ſuch Iourney-man Printer, or other perſon as aforeſaid, their or any of their Widows, ſhall not in any wiſe be admitted a Penſioner to the ſaid Society.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> it is hereby further Ordained, That no perſon whatſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever, being a Member of this Company (Except his Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties Printers, or their Aſſigns, who pretend an Intereſt in the Statutes and Abridgment of Statutes by Grant from the King) ſhall at any time or times hereafter, print or cauſe to be printed the Statute-Books or common Law-Books herein after named;
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:96532:13"/> That is to ſay, <hi>Poultons Statutes, Cook</hi> upon <hi>Littleton, Cooks Entries</hi> or <hi>Reports,</hi> or any other Law-Books whatſoever, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>unto <hi>Edward Atkins</hi> 
                     <abbr>Eſq</abbr> or his Aſſigns, now are or hereafter may be intituled, by vertue of Letters Patents to him granted, Vpon pain that every Member of this Company (Except the Kings Prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters and their Aſſigns aforeſaid) offending in the premiſſes, ſhall forfeit and pay to the Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> for every Impreſſion of the ſaid Books before particularly named, or of any other Law-Books granted in the ſaid Patent to the ſaid <hi>Edward Atkins,</hi> printed contrary to the meaning of this Order, the ſumme of Two hundred pounds of lawfull money of <hi>England,</hi> in Truſt for the ſaid <hi>Edward Atkins.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
               <head>
                  <hi rend="blackletterType">The By-Law</hi> to be Read at the Admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſtring of the Free-mans Oath, and a Printed Copy thereof to be delivered to every Member of the ſaid Company dealing in the <hi>Stationers</hi> Trade.</head>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>IT IS</hi> hereby Ordained, that no Member or Members of this Company ſhall hereafter knowingly Imprint or cauſe to be Imprinted any Book, Pamphlet, Portraicture, Picture or Paper whereunto the Law requires a Licenſe, without ſuch Licenſe as by the Law is directed for the Imprinting of the ſame.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> in Caſe any Member as aforeſaid ſhall henceforth know of the Imprinting, Binding, Stitching, Publiſhing or Diſperſing of any ſuch Book, Pamphlet, Portraicture, Picture or Paper as aforeſaid, ſuch Member or Members as aforeſaid, ſhall from time to time diſcloſe the ſame unto the Maſter or Wardens of the ſaid Company within Three dayes after the knowledge of ſuch Offence committed, together with the Name or Names of
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:96532:14"/> ſuch Perſon or Perſons ſo offending; Which ſaid Maſter or War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens upon ſuch Information given, ſhall cauſe the ſame to be en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tred in a Book hereafter mentioned, within ſix dayes after ſuch Information received, upon pain that every Perſon offending in either or any of theſe Caſes, and having a part in the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Stock of this Company, the Profits of ſuch part of his Stock for one year ſhall be ſequeſtred, and paid into the hands of the Maſter and Keepers, or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery or Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> to the uſe of the Poor of the ſaid Corporation: Vnleſs the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants, with the Conſent of <hi>Roger L'Eſtrange</hi> 
                     <abbr>Eſq</abbr> or ſuch Perſons as hereafter ſhall have the like Power concerning the Preſs com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted to them, as he now hath, upon hearing of the matter, ſhall according to the nature of the Offence think fit to mitigate the ſame.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND,</hi> if any Perſon or Perſons having no part in the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Stock of this Company, ſhall offend in either or any of the Caſes aboveſaid, Then ſuch Perſon or Perſons ſhall forfeit and pay to the Maſter and Keepers or Wardens and Comminalty of the Myſtery of Art of <hi>Stationers</hi> of the City of <hi>London,</hi> to the uſe of the Poor of the ſaid Corporation, the ſumme of Ten pounds; <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nleſs the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants, with the Conſent of the ſaid <hi>Roger L'Eſtrange</hi> 
                     <abbr>Eſq</abbr> or of ſuch Perſons as ſhall ſucceed him in his Authority and Power as aforeſaid, upon hearing of the Matter ſhall according to the Nature of the Offence think fit to mitigate the ſame.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND,</hi> if any Perſon having and receiving a Penſion from this Company, or that hath or ſhall have any of the Companyes Money in his or their hands upon Loan, ſhall offend in either or any of the Caſes aboveſaid, Then ſuch <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ſion ſhall be taken away from ſuch Penſioner, and all ſuch Money which ſuch perſon or perſons as aforeſaid, doth or ſhall owe to this Company, ſhall as ſoon as the ſame ſhall become due, be forthwith called in, and in default of payment, a ſpeedy courſe at Law ſhall be taken by this Company for the Recovery thereof.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND,</hi> if any Printer ſhall offend herein, ſuch Printer ſhall not for One year next following ſuch Offence, nor after One year expired without the Conſent of the Maſter, Wardens and
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:96532:14"/> Aſſiſtants be employed in the doing of any work for or belonging to the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Stock of this Company.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="order">
                  <p>
                     <hi>AND</hi> be it further Ordained, That for the Future ſhall be kept by the Clerk of this Company, two Books; In one of which ſhall be fairly written ſuch Informations given to the Maſter or Wardens as aforeſaid; and in the other ſhall be fairly written, what Seditious, Scandalous, Treaſonable and unlicenſed Books and Pamphlets ſhall be ſeiz'd, and Diſcoveries thereof made, toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther with the Number of them, and the Perſons from whom they were ſeiz'd: which Books ſhall be ſhewen to <hi>Roger L'Eſtrange</hi> 
                     <abbr>Eſq</abbr> when he ſhall think fit.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
               <div type="oath">
                  <head>The Maſters Oath.</head>
                  <p>YOU ſhall ſwear to be good and true to our Sovereign Lord the Kings Majeſty that now is, and to his Heirs and Succeſſors, Kings or Queens of this Realm: And that you ſhall as Maſter well and truely Order and Govern all the Fellowſhip of this Myſtery and Company of <hi>Stationers,</hi> whereof you are choſen Maſter for this preſent Year, according to your beſt skill and Judgement: And the good Rules and Ordinances of this Company you ſhall keep, and ſee to be kept to the beſt of your power.</p>
                  <p>So help you God.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="oath">
                  <head>The Wardens Oath.</head>
                  <p>YOU ſhall ſwear to be good and true to our Sovereign Lord the Kings Majeſty that now is, and to his Heirs and Succeſſors, Kings or Queens of this Realm: And that you ſhall as Wardens well and truely Order and Govern all the Fellowſhip of the Myſte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry and Company of <hi>Stationers,</hi> whereof you are now choſen War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens for this preſent Year, according to the beſt of your skill and knowledge: And the good Rules and Ordinances of this Company, you ſhall keep, and ſee to be kept according to the beſt of your power.</p>
                  <p>So help you God.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="oath">
                  <pb n="26" facs="tcp:96532:15"/>
                  <head>The Free-mens Oath.</head>
                  <p>YOU ſhall ſwear to be good and true to our Sovereign Lord the Kings Majeſty that now is, and to his Heirs and Succeſſors, Kings or Queens of this Realm, and to be Obedient to the Maſter and Wardens of this Company in all lawfull manner: You ſhall alſo keep ſecret all the lawfull Counſel of this Fellowſhip: And all man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner of lawfull Rules and Ordinances for the good Ordering of the ſaid Fellowſhip ye ſhall to the beſt of your skill obſerve and keep, and to your power ye ſhall be well willing, helping and furthering to the good Governance and Wealth of the ſame Fellowſhip, and ſhall not be party or privy in any Counſel or Device that may be to the hurt or hinderance of the ſame Company, or to the over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>throwing and breaking of the good Laws and Ordinances of the ſame: But all ſuch Practices, Counſels and Devices you ſhall diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cloſe to the ſaid Maſter and Wardens of the Company, and them labour to hinder and break ſo much as in you lyeth.</p>
                  <p>So help you God.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="oath">
                  <head>The Clerks Oath.</head>
                  <p>YOU ſhall ſwear to be good and true to our Sovereign Lord the Kings Majeſty that now is, and to his Heirs and Succeſſors, Kings or Queens of this Realm: You ſhall be Obedient in all law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>full manner to the Maſter and Wardens of this Fellowſhip: And you ſhall make true Entries of all ſuch things as you ſhall be com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded by the Maſter, Wardens and Aſſiſtants for the time being, and faithfully keep all the Books and Records: And in all other things you ſhall well and truely demean your ſelf as Clerk of this Company, and the ſame to execute according to the beſt of your skill and knowledge.</p>
                  <p>So help you God.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="oath">
                  <pb n="27" facs="tcp:96532:15"/>
                  <head>The Beadles Oath.</head>
                  <p>YOU ſhall ſwear to be good and true to our Sovereign Lord the Kings Majeſty that now is, and to his Heirs and Succeſſors, Kings or Queens of this Realm: You ſhall be in all lawful man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner obedient to the Maſter and Wardens of this Company; and all perſons of the ſaid Company when you are commanded you ſhall in due time lawfully ſummon and warn to the Aſſemblies of the ſame. All the lawful Counſel alſo and Secrets of this Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany you ſhall well and truely keep: And all other lawful things appertaining to your Office you ſhall well and faithfully doe.</p>
                  <p>So help you God.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="oath">
                  <head>The Oath of an Aſſiſtant.</head>
                  <p>YOU ſhall ſwear to be good and true to our Sovereign Lord the Kings Majeſty that now is, and to his Heirs and Succeſſors, Kings or Queens of this Realm: And that you ſhall according to your beſt Skill and Judgement, with your Advice or otherwiſe, well and truely Aſſiſt the Maſter and Wardens of this Company, when there ſhall be Occaſion: And the good Rules and Ordinan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces of this Company you ſhall keep, and ſee to be kept to the beſt of your power.</p>
                  <p>So help you God.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="approbation">
            <p>ALL which Orders, Rules, Ordinances and Oaths, in manner and form aforeſaid made, <hi rend="blackletterType">Wee</hi> the ſaid Lord Chancellor of <hi>England,</hi> and Lord Chief Juſtices of either Bench, have ſeen, peruſed and Examined, and in Order to the preventing and avoiding of the Penalty inflicted by
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:96532:16"/> the aforeſaid Statute upon the Execution of Ordinances not approved, as by the ſaid Act is directed, (And as far forth as by Law we may) we do approve, ratifie and confirm.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi rend="blackletterType">In Witneſs</hi> whereof, to theſe Preſents, We the ſaid Lord Chancellor of <hi>England,</hi> and Lord Chief Juſtices of either Benches, have hereunto ſubſcribed our Names, and ſet our Seals, <date>the Second day of <hi>February,</hi> in the Thir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tieth Year of the Reign of our Sovereign Lord <hi>Charles</hi> the Second, by the Grace of God King of <hi>England, Scot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land, France</hi> and <hi>Ireland, Defender of the Faith,</hi> &amp;c. Anno<expan>
                        <am>
                           <g ref="char:abque"/>
                        </am>
                        <ex>que</ex>
                     </expan> Dom. 1677.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>
                  <list>
                     <item>H. Finch, C.</item>
                     <item>Ri. Rainsford.</item>
                     <item>Fra. North.</item>
                  </list>
               </signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
